Tran Trung Kien (William)

Birthday: 1993 Gender: Male

Email: <u>kien@kienoi.com</u> Phone: +84888815552



PERSONAL STATEMENT

William is currently solution development of data entry project for Banking and Insurance company in Vietnam.

Since 2015, he has been working internationally in various domains including telecommunication, automotive, IoT, Banking and Insurance. He has 4 years of experience as embedded software test engineer. He has ability to quickly adapt to different project environments, work well independently and as part of a team. Ability to prioritize tasks and meet deadlines. Experience with unit testing, system testing and generated test reports. Experienced over automotive testing tools that include RTRT, Vector Cast, Canoe. Report and track the issues using ALM, Clear-case, ClearQuest, HP QC. Experienced with requirement specifications and changing requirement sheets using IBM DOORS tool.

- * Proactively, honestly, self-motivation, like challenging, willing to take responsibility.
- * Worked on-site in India and willing to work on-site for short, long term.
- * Experienced in on-site working for international company and stakeholders.
- * Work-life integration styles.

EXPERIENCE

DIGI-TEXX VIETNAM

Anna Building, QTSC, District 12, HCMC

Solution Development

November 2019 – Present

I currently working as solution development in building BPO, Data Entry solutions and provide data entry solutions consultant for Vietnam market.

- Conduct study, elicit customer jobs to understand their pain, gain and expectation.
- Create the technical proposal, estimate size, effort, resources and cost and support in commercial proposal to acquire new projects.
- Explore new technology and solution, propose new ideas on system and process improvements.
- Testing and Measurement.
- Work on delivering POCs to support new ideas and innovation.

Skills utilized: BPMN, API, Webservices, JSON/XML, OCR, ML/AI, Network, DevOps, CI/CD, and Security.

<u>Key achievement:</u> Within 3 months timeline, implement and deploy 2 data entry and scanning solutions for a banking and an insurance company in Vietnam. Reduce the operation resource, improve quality and TAT of project.

Hella Vietnam Co., Ltd

6 Nguyen Thi Minh Khai, Dakao, District 1, HCMC

Software Test Engineer

November 2018 – November 2019

- Produce: PEPS (Passive Entry Passive Start) GCAPE (Global Car Access Passive Entry)
- Integration Test and Software Test
- Requirement analysis, review requirement, design test case, implement, execute test case, write automation test script, analyses failure and bugs report.
- CANoe, PTC, DOORS, Winldea, Test Bench

Robert Bosch Engineering and Business Solution Vietnam

364 Cong Hoa Street, Tan Binh District, HCMC

Automotive Embedded Software Test Engineer

November 2016 - November 2018

- Software component Unit testing for Automotive Steering Control System, Boost Recuperation System.
- Requirement analysis, design, implement, execute test case, analyses failure and bugs report
- Analysis / debugging of embedded software
- Communicate with customer, co-ordinate team activities, and handle day-to-day work efficiently and independently
- Use C, RTRT Rational Test Real Time, AEEE, Python, ISO26262, ISTQB, ClearCase, ALM, JIRA, DOORS, ClearQuest.

<u>BMI 2018</u> – Shirm Inssurance: Top 1 idea and top 3 BMI Hackathon 2018. Team (Mr. Vo Xuan Huy, Mrs. Nhu, Mr. Bien)

<u>CSR - Organizer</u> - Come to Suburb 2016 and 2017 - Thanh Loc Ward, District 12, HCMC - *Dec 2016* - *Dec 2017*

Organize activities and support facilities for children. Host the knowledge contest "Ring the Golden Bell". Clean up the polluted channels and streets in Thanh Loc Ward.

MDN SAVIWAVE Ltd

32 Ton That Tung, District 1, HCMC

Software Test Engineer

July 2015 - October 2016

- Creating and executing test plans / test cases
- Do manual test and automation test
- Developing automation test by Python
- Reporting issues on issue tracking system
- Daily report, weekly report
- Validate embedded software (RTOS, software stacks)
- Used Python, C, Open AT Platform, RTOS, Protocol (TCP, FTP, HTTP, POP, SMTP, GPRS)
 Window, Linux.

EDUCATION

Sep 2011 - July 2015

Can Tho University - Major is Computer Engineering - Grade: 3.0/4.0

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

- The degree of engineer: Computer Engineering
- TIIC MCU Design Contest 2014 Texas Instrument
- Volunteer of Learning Resource Center at CTU (2011 2015)
- Success through superior professionalism (23 October 2017)

- BMI Hackathon in Robert Bosch Engineering and Business Solution Vietnam (November 2018)

KEY SKILLS

Skills

- Strong in software testing skills, testing techniques
- Good English communication skills
- Analytical and problem-solving
- Debugging
- The ability to learn quickly
- Teamwork, Leadership
- ISO26262, ISTQB, ASPICE, AGILE.

Programming Language

- Strong in C programming for Embedded Software
- PTU script language in RTRT
- Python Script
- Open AT Platform
- API, RPA, Robot Framework, Airflow, Django, Flask, PHP, NodeJS, React, Java.

Micro-controller

- Raspberry Pi 2, Galileo Intel, Arduino, MSP430, Nuvoton NUC140,
- SIM900, ZigBee, Sensor (HMC5883L, MPU6050, Temperature, pH, Oxygen)

IDE

- Canoe, Winldea, RTRT Rational Test Real Time
- Clear-Case, AEEE, DOOR, ClearQuest, RADAR, ALM, HP Quality Center
- Arduino IDE, Galileo IDE, PTC

PERSONAL INTERESTS

R&D | Innovation | CSR | Traveling |